# CHRISTOPHER JAY DE CLARO

Software Engineer | Professor



+63 931 208 6674



cjdeclaro16@gmail.com



Talisay, Batangas



linkedin.com/in/cjdeclaro



github.com/cjdeclaro

### SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JS, React, Angular, Typescript
- · Ruby on Rails, Ruby, PHP
- SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, PHPMyAdmin
- · Adobe CC, MS Office Suite, Google Office Suite
- Git, Github, Circle CI, SonarCloud, Datadog
- · Jira, Slack
- Android Studio
- Figma, Adobe XD, Canva
- AWS Services
- Artificial Intelligence

# **EDUCATION**

#### **BS Information Technology**

Polytechnic University of the Philippines 2015 - 2019

#### **Master in Information Technology**

Polytechnic University of the Philippines OU 2021 - Present

### PROFILE

Hi! I'm a Software Engineer, Professor, and a Designer. I am a Bachelor of Science in Information Technology Graduate from the Polytechnic University of the Philippines. I Develop multi-platform software applications. I created apps in academic and professional fields and presented them on the national level. Currently focused on Web Development using Ruby on Rails and React, while doing academic research on Artificial Intelligence. Working and communicating with people is one of my greatest strengths.

### EXPERIENCES

#### **IT PROFESSOR**

Polytechnic University of the Philippines - Sto Tomas, Batangas, PH Nov 2019 - Present

Tasked to hone the skills of the next generation scholars at the Philippines' first Polytechnic University in the field of Information Technology. I specialize in courses in the fields of Programming, Software Engineering, Digital Design, and related practices. Currently handling specialized courses on Artifical Intelligence.

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

#### Freelance

Dec 2023 - Present

Deployed in a team comprised of Software Engineers, QA Specialists, and UI/UX Engineers to develop Web Based applications primarily using Ruby on Rails and React

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

**Quipper Philippines,** Makati City, PH Apr 2021 - Dec 2023

Deployed in a team comprised of Software Engineers, QA Specialists, and UI/UX Engineers to develop a Learning Management System using technologies such as Ruby on Rails, React, AWS Services, CircleCI, Docker, etc

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

You\_Source Inc, Makati City, PH Mar 2019 - Apr 2021

Deployed in a team comprised of Software Engineers, Quality Assurance Specialists, and UI/UX Engineers to work in a Service-based Web Application using Ruby on Rails and Angular.

# **PROJECTS**

#### **MAPPING THE PHILIPPINES**

#### github.com/cjdeclaro/mapping-the-ph

Mapping the Philippines is a project that aims to visualize various aspects of the Philippines using geographic data. It is structured to support multiple sub-projects, each with a specific theme or dataset.

## AWARDS

- Cum-Laude PUP Sto Tomas Batangas
- Finalist Smart Communications Inc's 2019 Annual Sweep App Dev Awards
- 5th Placer TrendMicro's 2018 University CTF Hacking Competition
- Finalist LRT1's 2018 HackaTren Pre-hack Competition
- Champion iSIte CALABARZON's 2018 Regional C++ Programming Competition
- 5th Placer NAST DOST's 2017 Salinlahi Evolution App Dev Competition
- 2nd Placer PUP Sta Mesa 2017 University Wide IT Quiz Bee

